<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Gerhard Groenewald</title>
    <link>/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Gerhard Groenewald</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>gerhard@anjurad.com (Gerhard Groenewald)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gerhard@anjurad.com (Gerhard Groenewald)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gerhard@anjurad.com (Gerhard Groenewald)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Gerhard Groenewald.
I am a management consultant in the UK telecommunications industry, specialising in data science.
My résumé provides more detail about my career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gerhard@anjurad.com (Gerhard Groenewald)</author>
      <guid>/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>I have a ‘go-to’ list of quality and up-to-date sources of information that I continuously draw upon either as a reference, for training, detecting patterns and trends, or comparison and evaluation.
I have mapped the list to the data science process, and the skills and knowledge supporting it. I hope that it saves you time and help focus on relevant and critical aspects using quality, vetted information.
The following graph provides an outline of the data science process and the skills and knowledge required to practice it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Résumé</title>
      <link>/page/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gerhard@anjurad.com (Gerhard Groenewald)</author>
      <guid>/page/resume/</guid>
      <description>Schooling and Early Career I was born and raised in Cape Town.
I excelled at music and reached licentiate level by the time I graduated from school. During my year of compulsory military service, I was selected to an elite group in the South African Air Force (SAAF) and performed 255 concerts on tour throughout South Africa.
After completing national service I remained in Pretoria and joined the SAAF Band as it paid very well for a 19-year-old and allowed enough time to focus on studies too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>